- Jesse .
You get in this house right now .
Mom .
Right now .
No .
Who are you ?
- Well I 'm , I 'm Mrs. Voorhees ,
an old friend of the Christys .
- No , no , they 're all dead , they 're all dead .
- All right , all right , I 'll go look .
- No , no , please don 't leave me . They 'll kill you too .
- I 'm not afraid .
No .
- Did you know that a young boy drowned
the year before those two others were killed ?
The counselors weren 't paying any attention .
They were making love while that young boy drowned .
His name was Jason .
I was working the day that it happened , preparing meals .
Near , I was the cook .
Jason should 've been watched , every minute .
He was ...
He wasn 't a very good swimmer .
We can go now , dear .
Sweet , innocent Jason .
My only child .
Jason .
You let him drown . You never paid any attention .
Look what you did to him .
- No .
- Kill her , Mommy , kill her .
She can 't hide .
No place to hide .
Get her , Mommy , get her .
Kill her .
- Two of my men pulled you out of the lake .
We thought you were dead too .
You remember very much ?
- The boy , is he dead too ?
Who ?
- The boy , Jason .
- Jason ?
- In the lake , the , the one who attacked me .
The one who pulled me underneath the water .
- Ma 'am , we didn 't find any boy .
- Then he 's still there .
God .
Hello .
Hi mom .
I know , I 'm sorry .
I meant to call earlier , but I fell asleep .
Really , I 'm fine .
I need a little time alone , that 's all .
I know you and Dad worry , and I appreciate that .
Come on Mom , we 've been through all of this before .
I just have to put my life back together ,
and this is the only way I know how .
Look .
Mom , please , it 's getting late
and I really don 't wanna get into it .
I 'll call you tomorrow . Bye .
Mom
Hello ?
Cute .
You want something ' to eat ?
All right , keep your eyes peeled .
I think we 're gettin ' close .
Hey , there 's the gas station .
- Okay , let 's call Ted .
Hey Teddy buddy , we just rolled in .
Yeah , yeah , Sandra 's here .
- Hi , Ted .
- Hey , so you 're gonna come down and get us , or what ?
Yeah , okay . Okay , give me the directions .
Here , wait , wait , wait , wait , wait . All right , all right .
Okay , go ahead , I 'm ready .
All right , Old North Road , and then look for a Dairy Queen .
Okay .
And then over -
- I told the others . They didn 't believe me .
You 're all doomed . You 're all doomed .
- What ?
No , nothing , no .
No , go ahead , no . All right .
So , all right , covered bridge .
Okay . Then what ?
All right , so then past an old cemetery , right .
And then um , left down an old dirt road half a mile .
My god , they 're towing us .
Shit . Ted , I 'll call ya back .
- Hey . - Hey wait !
Hey . - Mister !
Hey !
- This is my truck .
Come on , this is my truck .
Asshole , this is my truck .
This is my truck !
- Welcome to God 's country .
- You wretch .
- Thanks , Max .
Max owns the gas station . He 's crazy too .
- I should 've known .
- Well this is great to see you guys .
It 's gonna be just like old times .
- Yeah , that 's what I 'm afraid of .
- Okay , help me load my gear , we 'll split for the camp ,
okay ? - Okay .
So Ted , what 's the scoop ?
- Well , I like that guy Paul that 's running the course .
Yeah , he 's okay .
He 's kinda macho though , you know .
He takes the whole thing very seriously .
City camp counselor , guys .
We 'll probably all get a brownie badge to wear
if we survive .
- If we survive ?
- That 's right .
What , didn 't I tell you I 'm gonna be a second assistant ?
No .
Wait , listen , listen .
Okay , so there 's a bear and a rabbit in the woods , see ,
and they 're both taking a dump .
So the bear looks down at the rabbit and says ,
" Excuse me , Mr. Rabbit , do you any problem
with shit sticking to your fur ? "
And the rabbit says , " No , Mr. Bear , I don 't . "
So the bear wiped his ass with the rabbit .
- What the heck is that ?
Where 'd this sucker come from ?
- I don 't know . Let 's move it .
- This place is spooky .
It looks like somebody dragged it out here .
Yeah , but with what ?
- Hey you guys , look at this .
- That 's Camp Blood .
This place is on the same lake as we 're gonna be .
- Camp Blood ?
- Hey , isn 't that the place - - Let 's get outta here .
We 're going to be late .
- Can 't we take a look ?
No way .
- What 's the problem ?
You don 't wanna hear about it man , believe me .
Not before lunch .
- You need some help ?
No , it 's okay , I got it .
Thanks anyhow .
Hi .
- Okay , let 's settle down .
It 's great to have you all here
at our new counselor training center .
You 've all worked as counselors at one camp or other .
Terry , Vickie , you two were upstate last summer , right ?
Scott , hi , good to see you here , buddy .
You need it .
And Mark , I know we worked a season
or two together , right ?
- Okay , the rest of you ,
I 'm sure I 'll get to know soon enough .
And I 'm also sure there 's one thing
I don 't have to tell any of you .
Being a counselor isn 't the gravy summer job
everybody thinks it is .
And what we 're gonna do over the next two weeks ,
if the rest of my staff ever shows up , is go back to basics .
Survival , first aid , boating , archery , rifle range ,
all of it .
What the hell ?
I 'll be right back .
- Hi . I 'm late .
- Well , what is this crap , Ginny ?
You 're supposed to be my assistant .
Everyone else got here hours ago .
- I said I was sorry .
- You did ?
- I 'm sorry . Okay ?
But my car 's sick .
- Well , you could 've called .
- Paul , I tried , but your phones aren 't even working yet .
Okay um ,
get your gear stowed and helped me outside , okay ?
- Paul , look , the course starts today , right ?
Well here I am .
And I promise you ,
I 'll never , ever be late again in my entire life .
Is it a deal ?
- All right , all right , what the hell .
Look , Ginny , I was starting to worry about you .
- Bullshit , Paul .
Ginny , put your car in the lot , okay ?
This place is starting to look like a Burger King .
Now , where was I ?
You were about to give your
let 's keep our shit together speech .
Mr. Holt .
- Right . - Right .
- Okay , look , a few words about safety .
Axes , knives , lanterns , saws ,
they can all be trouble .
Their misuse is the main cause
of camp accidents .
Take care of your equipment and it 'll take care of you .
Now a word of caution
about our friends in the forest .
Among other things , this is bear country .
And , contrary to what everybody hears , bears are dangerous .
That means no food fights .
- Change often , food odors cling to clothing .
If you 're a woman , don 't use perfume .
And keep clean during your menstrual cycle .
Having trouble ?
You gotta treat ' em gentle , just like kids .
Use a little of that child psychology you 're majoring in .
Try it .
- It 's more fun using that child psychology on you .
You 're such a sucker for it .
- Thanks a bunch .
- I don 't wanna scare anyone .
But I 'm gonna give it to you straight about Jason .
His body was never recovered from the lake after he drowned .
And if you listen to the old timers in town ,
they 'll tell you he 's still out there ,
some sort of demented creature ,
surviving in the wilderness , full grown by now ,
stalking , stealing what he needs .
Living off wild animals and vegetation .
Some folks claim they 've even seen him , right in this area .
The girl who survived that night at Camp Blood ,
that Friday the 13th , she claims she saw him .
She disappeared two months later , vanished .
Blood was everywhere .
No one knows what happened to her .
Legend has it that Jason saw his mother
beheaded that night , and he took his revenge .
A revenge that he 'll continue to seek
if anyone ever enters his wilderness again .
And by now , I guess you all know ,
we 're the first to return here .
Five years , five long years , he 's been dormant .
And he 's hungry .
Jason 's out there ,
watching ,
always on the prowl for intruders .
Waiting to kill , waiting to devour .
Thirsty for young blood .
- You scumbag . - Hey come back , come back .
Okay look , now , now that we got that out of our system ,
okay , I don 't wanna hear any more about it .
That 's ancient history .
Jason drown , Mrs. Voorhees was killed ,
and Camp Crystal Lake is off limits .
You got it ? - Yeah .
Got you ?
What 'd you think ?
- Second act needs work .
Too bad .
Come on , come on , come on .
Come on .
You got a shot .
You got ' em now , you got ' em .
Yeah .
- Come on . - Go on .
- Thanks a lot . - Damn , man .
- Thanks a lot , all right , thanks a lot .
- Hey . - Next .
- Hi Terry , do you wanna dance ?
- No , thank you .
- Hi there . How ' bout you ?
Do you wanna dance ?
So there I was , sitting in this fast food joint ,
thinking to myself , Scott old boy ,
what are you gonna do with the rest of your life ?
Hey , I 'm striking out all over the place .
- Well , I think I 've got you , check .
- Wrong , white man . Checkmate .
Well , what next ?
I could get my arm broken by Mark .
My brand 's ponged by a electronical wizard .
Or bed .
Goodnight , Paul , see you in the morning .
- Jeff , I just gotta see that place .
- What place ?
- That camp , Camp Blood .
You 're crazy .
I 've just got to .
Maybe there is something to that legend .
Come on , I 'm serious .
- No way . You 're not gettin ' me out there .
Besides , Paul said it was off limits .
We 'll see .
- Hello ?
Who 's there ?
Paul , goddammit ,
what do you think you 're - - Hey , hey , hey , calm down .
You 'll wake the natives .
I 'm not supposed to be fraternizing with the staff .
- I won 't tell .
- I missed you , Ginny .
And I really was worried when you didn 't show on time .
Paul , there 's something I think I should tell you .
I just saw you run .
You can go first .
Hey , hey , hey , hey , come on , come on .
Blow your whistle .
- Hey , what 's the matter , guys ?
Jeff , the women are showing you up .
What 's the matter with ya ?
Hey .
- We 're gonna take this side and you loop back to town .
We got about a half a mile , and then we 're gonna have lunch .
Try to stay on this trail ,
because there 's a lot of poison ivy along here ,
we don 't have to - - How far are we from camp ?
- Hey , you 're gonna trip on that one .
You hungry ?
Mr. Hunger now - - Yeah , she 's hungry .
What did you have for lunch ?
Ted 's probably gonna cook .
- Anyway . - Go on .
Just watch out for the fish -
You got it ?
Trouble with that ?
After lunch , we 're gonna do some more running .
- Here you go , Ted .
- Thank you , dear .
Thank you .
- Come and get ' em .
- I 'm here .
- Muffin ? Here girl .
Muffin ?
Terry , lunch .
- Okay , I 'm coming .
You better watch out .
- Jeff . - What ?
- You ready ?
- For what ?
- Camp Blood .
- I thought we weren 't suppose to go near that place .
Come on , it 's only a short walk .
They 'll never know we 're gone .
Jeff , I 'm serious . I really wanna see it .
Look , when we get back to the city
we can tell everyone we were there .
Come on you chicken shit .
You better watch out .
Woo .
Let 's roll , woo !
- Okay , let 's go .
Woo !
- Woo !
- Okay you guys , I got one .
Ready ? - What ?
- What 's green and red and goes a hundred miles an hour ?
- What ?
- A frog in a blender .
Ha , ha , that wasn 't funny .
- Okay , okay . What 's brown and sits on a piano ?
- Your face .
- No , Beethoven 's last movement .
Ew .
Yuck .
- This must be it .
- Yeah .
My god .
What is it ?
- Looks like a dog .
It 's too mangled to tell .
What do you think did it ?
Wild animal , I guess .
- What are you kids doin ' out here ?
You 're gonna have to keep your people
away from that place , Holt , it 's condemned .
Next time I catch anybody over there
I 'm gonna have to run ' em in .
- He told us that we 're -
- I 'll handle this , Jeff .
- Might just get a warrant against you .
Really ?
- Look , Holt , people say what you do with these kids
is great , you got a good reputation .
But if I was you , I 'd have located in the next county .
You 're too close .
Things have been quiet for five years
and that 's the way we wanna keep it .
- So do I officer , so do I.
Okay you two , take off
and I 'll talk to you at dinner , all right ?
- We 'll never do it again , sir .
- Thanks , Mr. Holt .
- You 're not even gonna reprimand ' em ?
No punishment ?
What kinda place is this ?
- Ginny ?
Yes , Paul .
- No seconds on dessert for Jeff and Sandra tonight .
- You okay ?
Should we tell Terry ?
You know , about what we saw ?
No way .
As far as I 'm concerned , we didn 't see a thing .
- Hey ! Come here .
No !
My god .
No .
Anybody want an apple -
- Look at this shit .
Okay , people , today was fun and games , right ?
Sure .
- Now I like to start you out slow , ease you into it .
Tomorrow we 'll get serious .
- Anybody who wants a last night on the town ,
now 's your chance .
Yes .
- Okay , who else ? We only have two cars .
- Here , here . - I do .
And by the way , our wanderers have volunteered
to stay behind and watch the camp .
Isn 't that nice of them ?
How nice .
- I think I 'll stay too , Muffin may show .
- Well , I 'm gonna go change , you guys .
- You know , I 'm pretty tired .
I think I 'll stick around , too .
David , could you get me
another cup of coffee ? - Don 't drink too much .
- Sure .
Move along .
Hey , you staying ?
- Yeah , nothing spoils a party faster than a drunk
in a wheelchair .
- That 's crap . Look , we can go together if you want .
- I appreciate that .
But I 'm in training .
- Then I 'm staying too .
- Suit yourself .
So how ' bout it second in command , are you coming ?
- You buying ?
- Sure .
- You got a deal . - Okay .
- Can I have the keys ?
Beer time !
- Take it easy . - Later , guys .
- Have fun . - Have a good time .
I 'll have a Jack for ya .
- See ya later .
Bring back my truck
in one piece . - Bring me a beer .
- I 'm going for a walk .
- We 'll wait up for you , all right ?
- Let 's go , scooter .
Now I know how you can afford tuition
to grad school .
You always find some fool to fix your car
and buy you a beer .
You got it .
- Muffin ?
- All right . - Good .
We 're there .
- Here we are . - All right , yeah .
Woo !
- Woo ! - All right , we 're here .
Let 's find some beer .
Everybody get out for some beers ,
it 's all right .
Yippee .
- Come on , Mark . Come on .
Come on , come on .
- Chicken wings .
- All right .
- Hey . - Cheater .
- Okay , okay , okay , do it over .
- All right .
- Jeff , don 't wear yourself out .
You wanna wrestle , come with me .
- Later , dude .
- Wanna take me on ?
- Sure , have a seat .
- I only want your fingers .
- What ?
- Take your pick .
- Hey .
- They 're Ted 's , it 's okay with him .
- Football and hockey . Which one do you prefer ?
- The one with the puck .
- You mean hockey ?
- Is that what you call it ?
- Hockey . What do you wanna play for ?
- Position .
- Looking for something ?
Come and get it .
- Give me my shirt , Scott .
If I get my hands on you . Scott .
It 's no longer funny , Scott .
Help .
Damn that Paul , him and his wilderness bullshit .
What can I do ?
- Get me down , that 's what .
I 'm gonna have to get a knife to cut the rope .
- Well hurry , okay ?
I oughta let you hang , you pervert .
- Come on Ter , give me a break .
- You gonna cut the crap ?
- Sure , anything . I promise .
- Okay .
Don 't go anywhere .
- Very funny .
Where is she ?
- Scott , I 'm gonna cut you down .
But I swear , if you ever do this to me again ,
I 'm gonna kill ya .
Scott ?
I think I 'm in love .
No , no , it 's just tremendous affection .
- Are you sure you don 't want me to clear those ?
- No , I 'm collecting these .
- Have it your way , honey .
I just don 't want the bar to fall down on you .
- Thanks .
- I think she likes you .
- I think so too .
- Yeah , and this whole thing 's ridiculous , really .
You know , two of our kids got hauled in today
' cause five years ago some girl , I don 't know ,
panics and falls out of a canoe .
It 's absurd .
- What if there is a Jason ?
Bullshit , Ginny .
- No , what if there is some kind of boy beast
running around Camp Crystal Lake ?
I mean , let 's try to think beyond the legend ,
put it in real terms .
I mean , what would he be like today ?
Some kinda out of control psychopath ?
A frightened retard ?
A child trapped in a man 's body ?
Let me out .
- He 'd be grown by now , right ?
Right .
- And you know , the only person he 'd ever known
was his mother .
Never went to school so he never had any friends .
I mean , she was everything to him .
- Yeah , deranged killer .
- No , no , no , you 're missing my whole point .
I mean , I doubt Jason would have even known
the meaning of death , or at least until that horrible night .
He must have seen the whole thing happen .
He must have seen his mother get killed ,
and all just ' cause she loved him .
I mean , isn 't that what her revenge was all about ?
Her sense of loss .
Her rage at what she thought happened .
Her love for him .
Bizarre , isn 't it ?
I mean , he must be out there right now
crying for her return , her resurrection .
Well , what do you think ?
- I think you 're drunk .
I 'll drink to that .
Hit us again , sweetheart .
- Not me .
You know , Paul , I 'm really serious about this though .
- Jason 's a legend , Ginny , a legend .
- Your turn . Three goals or you 're gonna lose .
- I 've heard that one before .
- Mark , what happened that you have to be in a chair ?
- Motorcycle accident , it paralyzed my legs .
- Is it permanent ?
- Doctor thinks so . I don 't .
I don 't intend to be in this thing the rest of my life .
- Just your legs ? Is everything else okay ?
I do all right , one way or another .
- Toke ?
- I 'm in training , remember ?
- For what ?
What does the winner get ?
- What does the winner want ?
- Guess .
Wanna stay together tonight ?
- I was just about to ask you .
- My cabin or yours ?
Tim 's in mine . I don 't think that would work out .
- We 've got the whole camp , we 'll find our own cabin .
Just give me a few minutes to get some things , okay ?
- Sure .
- I 'll be right back .
Dammit .
Terry , you turkey .
There you are .
- Vickie ?
Vickie , is that you ?
Vickie ?
- I gotta get some sleep . - So do 1 .
- You guys quittin ' already ?
- Ted , you 'll have me out till breakfast if I let you .
- I 'm gonna get a ride home with you , okay ?
- Okay .
- Night , Ted .
- Night , Ginny .
- When this place closes , you come straight back to camp .
You got it ?
- Yes , boss .
And let Maggie drive the pickup .
Yes , boss .
Okay , make a run for it .
Move it . - I 'm going , I 'm going .
Woo ! This thing better start .
You fixed it .
I know , that 's what worries me .
- Excuse me , are there any after hours places around here ?
- Sure are .
- There are , okay , thank you .
There are .
- Ooh .
Mark ?
Mark , where are you ?
Is anybody still here ?
Sandra ?
Jeff ?
Sandra ? Jeff ?
Sandra ?
No . Stop .
No .
Stop !
No !
No .
- Nice night .
- Yeah , I heard that one .
Woo , my god .
- What the hell are all the lights on for ?
- Paul , they wouldn 't have left the place like this .
Think something 's wrong ?
I 'll check upstairs .
- These kids smoke better dope than I do .
Paul !
- Yeah , Ginny , what ?
What is this , a joke ?
- They wouldn 't do anything like this .
- Ginny , come on .
- Wait for me .
- Kitchen light 's still on .
Must , must be the main fuse again .
- Paul , what 's going on here ?
- Nothing .
- Where is everybody ?
- I don 't know .
Rain 's stopping , we 'll go look for them .
- Paul , there 's someone in this room .
Paul , there 's someone in this fucking room !
My god , my god .
Paul , Paul ?
Paul .
Paul ?
Answer me !
No !
Come , the keys , the keys , they keys .
Come on , come on , come on , car .
Please start .
Come on , start .
My god .
My god . Please help me .
Jason , it 's all done , Jason .
You 've done your job well , mommy is pleased .
That 's a good boy .
Now come to Mommy . Come on .
Come on .
Mommy has been watching you .
Jason , Mother is talking to you .
- Jason , Mother is talking to you .
Come on .
That 's my boy .
Come , kneel down .
That 's a boy .
- Kneel down .
Kneel down .
- That 's my good boy .
That 's a good boy .
Good Jason .
- Ginny !
Come on , let 's go .
Ginny .
Jesus .
Come on , I 'll carry you . Come on .
Hey , hey , you 're all right .
- God , no .
- You 're , you 're , you 're okay .
You 're okay , you 're okay , Ginny , you 're all right .
Muffin .
Hi , Muffin .
Come here , Muffin .
Paul ?
Where 's Paul ?